In this video we make another excursion into reversing C programs. To be specific, we will
在这段视频中，我们又进行了一次，反转C程序的旅行。具体来说，
talk about the Global Offset Table (short GOT) and the Process Linkage Table (short
我们会讨论全局偏移表（GOT）
PLT)
和进程链接表（PLT）。
Let’s start by creating a very simple C program that just calls a couple of libc functions.
我们先创建一个非常简单的 C 程序，它只调用两个 libc 函数。
So I just write two printfs and an exit. These two functions are clearly external functions,
所以，我只写了两个 printf 和一个退出。
I haven’t defined them myself. And they come from libc. When I compile this binary
这两个函数显然是外部函数，我自己没有定义。他们来自 libc。当我编译这个二进制文件时，
with gcc libc will be dynamically linked to this binary. Which means that libc is not
使用 gcc，libc 将动态链接到此二进制文件。
included in the program. With `ldd` we can see the dynamic libraries referenced from
这意味着libc 不包括在程序中。使用“ldd”，
this binary and it shows that it wants libc, and it also displays the path on my system
我们可以看到来自这个二进制文件的动态引用，并显示说它想要libc，它还显示了我系统上，libc 二进制文件的路径位置。
where my libc binary is. This is great because then the program can be much smaller, and
这很好，因为这样程序就可以小得多，而且
libc can receive updates without having to recompile my binnary.
libc 可以在不重新编译二进制文件的情况下，接收更新。
But this also means, that the addresses in libc might be different for each version.
但这也意味着，libc 中的地址，对于每个版本来说，可能都是不同的。
So how can I compile a binary to assembler, when I have to know the exact address so I
所以，我怎样才能把一个二进制编译成汇编程序呢，因为我必须要知道确切地址，这样我才能创建一个call指令？
can create a call instruction? Well this is where the PLT and GOT comes into play.
好吧，这就是PLT和GOT 开始发挥作用的地方。
Let’s open this binary in hopper disassembler and let’s have a look at the main function.
让我们在 hopper 反汇编器中，打开这个二进制文件，看看 main 函数。
So first thing we notice is, where the hell are our printfs()? Why are there puts() calls?
所以，首先注意到的是，我们的 printfs() 到底在哪里？为什么有 puts() 调用？
Well the disassembler saw that we specified a constant string, nota dynamic format string,
反汇编程序，发现我们指定了一个常量字符串，而不是动态格式字符串，
thus decided to replace the printf with puts. But anyway, we have here our three function
因此，决定用 puts 替换 printf。但不管怎样，
calls and hopper decided to prefix the name of the call location with a j, probably for
我们这里有三个函数调用，还有 Hopper决定在调用位置的名称前面，加上一个 j，
jump. Not sure. So if we follow this call, we noticed that
可能是跳跃(jump)的意思。不确定。所以，如果我们跟着这个调用，
we don’t end up in libc puts. We are still in our binary. Also how would we, because
会注意到，我们不会以 libc 的 puts 结尾。我们仍然在二进制。我们会怎么做呢？
libc is not included in this binary. We landed in the plt section. The process linkage table.
因为 libc 不包含在此二进制文件中。我们会在PLT区着陆。进程链接表。
And the call to this here is immediatly followed up with a jump to an address stored at a nother
在这里的调用，会立即跳(jump)转到另一个人的地址
location. And this location got the name puts @ GOT. So let’s go there.
位置。这个位置的名字是 puts @ GOT。所以，让我们一探究竟。
Now we are in a segment called got. The global offset table. And the jump will jump to whatever
现在，我们进入了一个叫做 got 的部分。全局偏移表。方
address is stored here. And at the moment the address that is stored here is referencing
而这个跳，会跳到存储在这里的任何地址。此时，
an external symbol. So… So what are they doing here?
存储在这里的地址，正在指向一个外部符号。那么… 那么他们会在这里做啥呢？
During compilation we don’t know the address of puts, or exit. So we just create a function
在编译期间，我们不知道 puts 或 exit 的地址。所以，
trampoline. We call a location we know where it is, the PLT section. Which contains a jump
我们只创建一个函数 trampoline。我们会对一个我们知道它在哪里的位置(PLT区)进行调用。其中包含一个跳，
with the jump location referenced from this list (or table if you want). So all we have
来自该列表（或表，如果需要）指引的跳转位置。
to do, to be able to use external functions from a library, is somehow write the real
所以，我们要做到的，就是能够使用(libc)库中的外部函数，
address of the libc function in this table. And this is what is happening when we execute
以某种方式编写，libc函数的地址存于此表。
the binary. As you know by now, an ELF binary is not just plain assembler code. Before our
而这就是二进制的执行所会发生的。正如您现在所知道的，ELF二进制，不仅仅是简单的汇编程序代码。
codes get executed, the complicated ELF format is parsed and based on that the process is
在我们代码被执行之前，复杂的ELF格式会被解析，
set up by the kernel. And during that time references like that might get resolved.
基于由内核设置的进程。在这段时间内，这样的(地址)引用，可能会得到解决。
So let’s debug this binary. Let’s use hopper this time. First we set a breakpoint
所以，让我们调试这个二进制文件。这次我们用 hopper 吧。首先我们在 main 设置一个断点，
in main by clicking the red column in the right row. Then we open the debugger interface
单击对应行中的红色列就行。然后我们打开调试器界面，
with teh buttom on the top right. So let’s step forward until we follow the call to puts().
右上角有一个按钮。所以，让我们向前一步，直到我们跟到 puts() 的调用进行操作。
As expected we arrive in the PLT section and are just about to jump to the address referenced
如预期的那样，我们到达 PLT 部分，即将跳转到在全局偏移表中的引用地址。
in the global offset table. Let’s step further and let’s see what happens. Oh… nope.
让我们更进一步，看看会发生什么。哦… 不。
We don’t go to puts in libc. Somehow we ended up right after the jump and push a value
我们不去到 libc 的 puts。不知怎的，我们就在跳跃之后，
now on the stack. As you can see every PLT entry, also for our
推了一个值 now，在栈上。正如你看到的每一个PLT条目，
exit() function, we have this push of a number and then a jump to this address up here. And
也为我们的 exit() 函数的作用是：先推一个数字，然后跳到上面的这个地址。
when we follow this jump we end up in a function called _dl_runtime_resolve.
当我们跟着执行这个跳转后，最终以一个名为 _dl_runtime_resolve的函数结束。
We can use the proc file system to have a look at the memory maps of this process and
我们可以使用 proc 文件系统，来查看这个进程的内存映射，以及
we can see that the address from _dl_runtime_resolve belongs to this ld.so binary. The man page
我们可以看到，来自 _dl_runtime_resolve 的地址，是属于这个 ld.so二进制文件的。
for `ld.so` tells us that this is the dynamic linker/loader. So this library helps us to
“ld.so”手册，告诉我们这是动态链接器/加载程序。
set upt the external references to libc. This function does magic. No idea what it
所以，这个库帮助我们，设置对 libc 的外部引用。这个函数有魔力。
does in detail, but it will find the address of the puts() function in libc and updates
不知道它的详细操作，但它(应该)在 libc 里面，找到 puts() 函数的地址，
the GOT table and also executes puts. Now the second time we want to execute puts(),
并对 GOT 进行更新，而且执行了 puts。现在，第二次想要执行 puts()的话 ，
the GOT got updated and when we jump to the address stored in the global offset table
GOT 会有所更新，且当我们跳转到全局偏移量表中存储的地址后，
we end up in puts() from libc.
最终，会以libc中的 puts() 结尾。
This Global offset table is very very useful when writing exploits, because there are a
这个全局偏移表，在编写漏洞脚本时非常有用，
couple of things you can do with it.
因为你可以用它做一些事情。
First instance, we have an arbitrary write. We can write a value, we want, anywhere in
首先，我们有一个任意的写入。我们可以在内存任何地方，写入一个我们想要的值
memory. So you can simply overwrite the address in the global offset table for a certain function.
因此，您可以简单地覆盖某个函数，在全局偏移量表中的地址。
And the next time this function is called, the code will be redirected to whatever you
下次调用这个函数时，代码将被重定向到
entered in the global offset table.
你在全局偏移量表中的(任何)输入。
Let’s say you have a memory leak, for example through a format string exploit like from
假设您有一个内存泄漏，例如类似上一个视频的
the previous video. And the binary doesn’t use ASLR. Well, the system itself can still
格式字符串漏洞。二进制文件并没有使用aslr。
have ASLR enabled thus the location of libc will always be random. But the address of
嗯，系统本身仍然可以启用 aslr，因此 libc 的位置总是随机的。
the global offset table in your binary is always fixed. So when you can read from an
但是二进制文件中的，全局偏移量表里面的地址总是固定的。所以，
address you control, you can read an entry of the global offset table, which is an address
当你能读取您控制的地址，就可以读取全局偏移量表的一个条目，
in libc. Which you can then use to calculate the offsets to other locations of libc. Which
它是libc的一个地址。然后，您可以使用它，来计算到 libc 其他位置的偏移量。
is useful if you have to find rop gadgets or you want to do a return-to-libc.
对你必须查找 ROP 小工具，或要返回到libc 来说，非常有用。
And even if your binary uses ASLR, if you are able to leak an address of your binary
即使，您的二进制文件使用aslr，如果您能够泄漏二进制文件的地址
to defeat its address randomization, you can then calculate the offset to the global offset
为了避免地址随机化，您可以计算到，全局偏移表的偏移量。
table and then leak an address of libc that way.
然后，以这种方式泄漏libc的地址。
Sometimes you even have a buffer overflow or an arbitrary write in a function, but the
有时，甚至一个函数，有缓冲区溢出或任意写入，
function itself never returns, because it calls exit(), or loops forever, thus overwriting
但，函数本身并不会返回，因为它调用 exit() 或永远循环，
the return pointer on the stack doesn’t help to redirect code execution. That’s
那么，覆盖栈上的返回指针，对重定向代码执行没有帮助。
exactly the challenge in format level 4 of exploit-exercises.com. We cannot overwrite
这，正是 exploit-exercises.com 格式级别4的挑战。
the return address on the stack, so we have to rely on a different technique to gain control
我们不能覆盖栈上的返回地址，因此我们必须依赖不同的技术，
over the program execution.
在程序执行过程中，获得控制权。
See you next time when we use a format string vulnerability to overwrite an entry on the
下次再见，那时我们会使用格式字符串漏洞，覆盖全局偏移量表的一个条目，
global offset table to redirect code execution.
以达到代码执行的重定向。